<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!DOCTYPE article PUBLIC "-//Novell//DTD NovDoc XML V1.0//EN" "novdocx.dtd"
[
  <!ENTITY % NOVDOC.DEACTIVATE.IDREF "INCLUDE">
  <!ENTITY % entities SYSTEM "entity-decl.ent">
  %entities;
]>

<article id="article.vmdp.driver" lang="en">
 <?suse-quickstart color="suse"?>
 <title>Installation Guide</title>
 <articleinfo>
  <productnumber>&productnumber;</productnumber>
  <date>May 26, 2014</date>
 </articleinfo>
 
 <sect1 id="sec.vmdp.drivers.vdmp">
  <title>VMDP</title>
  <para>
   &sle; Virtual Machine Driver Pack contains Windows* disk and
   network device drivers, in order to enable the high-performance hosting of
   these unmodified guest operating systems on top of &sls;.
   Paravirtualized drivers for &sls; are available,
   but not included in this Driver Pack. Paravirtualized drivers for &sls; are distributed under an
   open source license and included in both physical and electronic media of &sls;
   and corresponding Customer Center update channels.
  </para>
  <sect2 id="sec.vmdp.drivers.introduction">
   <title>Introduction</title>
   <para>
    Virtualization allows the consolidation of Linux workloads on newer, more
    powerful, energy-efficient hardware. Paravirtualized operating systems
    such as &sls; are aware of the underlying virtualization platform, and can
    therefore interact efficiently with it. Unmodified operating systems are
    unaware of the virtualization platform and expect to interact directly
    with the hardware. Because this is not possible when consolidating
    servers, the hardware must be emulated for the operating system. Emulation
    can be slow, but it is especially troubling for high-throughput disk and
    network subsystems. Most performance loss occurs in this area.
   </para>
  </sect2>
  
  <sect2 id="sec.vmdp.drivers.performance">
   <title>Bringing performance</title>
   <para>
    The device drivers in &sle; Virtual Machine Driver Pack bring many of the
    performance advantages of paravirtualized operating systems to unmodified
    operating systems because only the paravirtualized device driver (not the
    rest of the operating system) is aware of the virtualization platform. For
    example, a paravirtualized disk device driver appears as a normal,
    physical disk to the operating system. However, the device driver
    interacts directly with the virtualization platform (with no emulation) to
    efficiently deliver disk access, allowing the disk subsystems
    to operate at near native speeds in a virtualized environment, without
    requiring changes to existing operating systems.
   </para>
  </sect2>
  
  <sect2 id="sec.vmdp.drivers.subscription">
   <title>Support Subscription</title>
   <para>
    The customer support you receive for the &sle; Virtual Machine Driver
    Pack is at the same level as your
    <ulink url="https://www.suse.com/support/programs/subscriptions/">SUSE Linux
    Enterprise support subscription</ulink>.
   </para>
  </sect2>
 </sect1>
 
 <!--VMDP certification -->
 <xi:include href="vmdp_certification.xml" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"/>

 <!--VMDP installation -->
 <xi:include href="vmdp_install.xml" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"/>

 <!-- VMDP QEMU Guest Agent -->
 <xi:include href="vmdp_qemu_guest_agent.xml" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"/>

 <!-- VMDP and v2v -->
 <xi:include href="vmdp_v2v.xml" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"/>
 
 <!-- VMDP best practices -->
 <xi:include href="vmdp_best_practices.xml" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"/>

 <!-- VMDP expert installation mode -->
  <xi:include href="vmdp_install_expert.xml" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"/>

 <!-- Step by step with Windows 7 -->    
 <xi:include href="vmdp_step_by_step.xml" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"/>

 <!-- Legal Stuff -->
 <xi:include href="common_copyright_sle.xml" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"/>

</article>
