<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE article PUBLIC "-//Novell//DTD NovDoc XML V1.0//EN" "novdocx.dtd"
[
  <!ENTITY % NOVDOC.DEACTIVATE.IDREF "INCLUDE">
  <!ENTITY % entities SYSTEM "entity-decl.ent">
  %entities;
]>

<sect1 id="sec.vmdp.best"> 
 <title>Best practices</title>
 <para>Best practices, usage and problem using VMDP.</para>
 <sect2 id="sec.vmdp.driver.winwizard.vmdp.problems">
  <title>Avoiding Problems with the Drivers</title>
  <para>                                                                                                
   To avoid problems and potential failure of the device drivers in the                                 
   driver pack, you should avoid the following actions:                                                 
  </para>
  <itemizedlist>
   <listitem>
    <para>                                                                                              
     Using the Device Manager to manage (update, disable, uninstall, etc.)                              
     the device drivers in the driver pack.                                                             
    </para>
   </listitem>
   <listitem>
    <para>                                                                                              
     Deleting driver files manually. Always use the uninstall utility (see                              
     <xref linkend="sec.vmdp.driver.winwizard.vmdp.uninstall" xrefstyle="SectTitleOnPage"/>).           
    </para>
   </listitem>
   <listitem>
    <para>                                                                                              
     Uninstalling the driver pack with the installation CD attached to the                              
     virtual machine.                                                                                   
    </para>
   </listitem>
   <listitem>
    <para>                                                                                              
     Canceling the installation when you see security alert that indicates                              
     that the Bus driver has not been properly signed. Click                                            
     <guimenu>Yes</guimenu> to continue the installation.                                               
    </para>
   </listitem>
   <listitem>
    <para>                                                                                              
     Upgrading the Linux<superscript>*</superscript> kernel of the virtual                              
     machine host without upgrading the driver pack at the same time.                                   
    </para>
   </listitem>
   <listitem>
    <para>                                                                                              
     Installing or uninstalling the driver pack by any other process than                               
     what is documented in this guide (see                                                              
     <xref linkend="sec.vmdp.driver.winwizard" xrefstyle="SectTitleOnPage"/>                            
     and                                                                                                
     <xref linkend="sec.vmdp.driver.winwizard.vmdp.uninstall" xrefstyle="SectTitleOnPage"/>).           
    </para>
   </listitem>
  </itemizedlist>
 </sect2>
 <sect2 id="sec.vmdp.best.before">
  <title>Before the installation</title>
  <para>                                                                                               
   Before installing &sle; Virtual Machine Driver Pack in your production                              
   environment, we strongly recommend that you run it in a test environment                            
   to ensure that it functions properly with your system.                                              
  </para>
 </sect2>
 <sect2 id="sec.vmdp.best.network">
  <title>Network configuration</title>
  <para>                                                                                               
   Do not give the server a fixed IP address before installing the driver                              
   pack, otherwise you have to switch to a different intermediate IP address                           
   before finishing the installation.                                                                  
  </para>
 </sect2>
 
</sect1>
