<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE sect1
[
  <!ENTITY % entities SYSTEM "entity-decl.ent">
    %entities;
]>
<sect1 xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" version="5.0" xml:id="sec-vmdp-driver-installation">
 <title>General installation</title>

 <para>
  The &productname; is available at <link xlink:href="https://www.suse.com/download/suse-vmdp/"/>
  for download as one binary file - a Windows self-extracting ZIP file (<emphasis>.exe</emphasis>
  extension). There is also an ISO image (<emphasis>.iso</emphasis>) for
  Windows* 2008 and newer that may be used for VMs running on KVM.
 </para>

 <sect2 xml:id="sec-vmdp-driver-prerequisites">
  <title>Prerequisites</title>
  <itemizedlist>
   <listitem>
    <para>
     &sls; 12 SP3 or later
    </para>
   </listitem>
   <listitem>
    <para>
     Fully virtualized Windows* virtual machines
    </para>
   </listitem>
  </itemizedlist>
 </sect2>

 <sect2 xml:id="sec-vmdp-driver-setup-exe">
  <title>Setup.exe installation instructions for KVM and Xen</title>
  <procedure>
   <step>
    <para>
     Download the Windows* <command>VMDP-WIN-VERSION.exe</command> file
     directly into your Windows* VM.
    </para>
   </step>
   <step>
    <para>
     Launch the <command>VMDP-WIN-VERSION.exe</command> to extract the
     installation program.
    </para>
   </step>
   <step>
    <para>
     Launch the <command>setup.exe</command> from the root of the newly created
     directory.
    </para>
   </step>
   <step>
    <para>
     Accept the <emphasis>EULA</emphasis> and follow the prompts to complete
     the driver installation.
    </para>
   </step>
   <step>
    <para>
     Reboot the VM when prompted by the installation program.
    </para>
   </step>
  </procedure>
 </sect2>

 <sect2 xml:id="sec-vmdp-driver-additionnal-info">
  <title>Additional KVM VirtIO setup instructions</title>
  <para>
   <command>Setup.exe</command> can be run with and without VirtIO devices
   present in the VM. If the devices are present in the VM when setup is run,
   the drivers are installed and loaded at that time. If the VirtIO devices are
   not present when setup is run, shut down the VM, add the VirtIO devices, and
   start the VM. After booting, Windows* will discover the new devices and load
   the previously installed drivers.
  </para>
  <para>
   To boot a running VM on a VirtIO disk, the VirtIO disk driver must be
   installed on a secondary/temporary (e:) VirtIO disk. After the driver is
   installed and controlling the disk, shut down the VM. From
   <guimenu>virt-manager</guimenu>, delete the secondary VirtIO disk and delete
   the IDE boot disk. Now add a disk of type VirtIO or VirtIO SCSI and give it
   the location for the boot disk. Boot the VM. The VirtIO driver will now be
   controlling the boot disk.
  </para>
  <warning>
   <title>Installation failure</title>
   <para>
    Failure to install a VirtIO disk driver on a secondary disk before changing
    the boot disk to a VirtIO or VirtIO SCSI disk will cause the VM to crash
    with bug check <emphasis>0x7b</emphasis> (inaccessible boot disk).
   </para>
  </warning>
 </sect2>

 <sect2 xml:id="sec-vmdp-driver-install-instruction">
  <title>Installation instructions for <literal>.vfd</literal> and <literal>.iso</literal></title>
  <para>
   A Windows* VM may attach the &vmdpa; <emphasis>iso</emphasis>. 
   The ISO contains VirtIO disk drivers for
   Windows* 2008 and newer. It also contains the full &vmdpa;
   <filename>*.exe</filename> file that contains all the VirtIO and Xen drivers
   for all supported Windows* platforms.
  </para>
 </sect2>

 <sect2 xml:id="sec-vmdp-driver-install-at-vm-creation">
  <title><literal>.iso</literal> for VirtIO boot disk installation at VM creation</title>
  <para>
   This method is only used for VMs running on KVM and is used to install the
   VirtIO disk driver on the boot disk while the VM is being installed.
  </para>
  <procedure>
   <step>
    <para>
     See
     <xref linkend="sec-vmdp-step-virt-manager" xrefstyle="SectTitleOnPage"/>
     for attaching an ISO, setting up<emphasis>Virtio Network</emphasis>, and a
     VirtIO disk for the Windows* VM.
    </para>
   </step>
   <step>
    <para>
      Add the <emphasis>iso</emphasis> to the VM configuration. 
    </para>
   </step>
   <step>
    <para>
     Set the boot disk to be of type VirtIO or VirtIO SCSI.
    </para>
   </step>
   <step>
    <para>
     Finish all other VM configuration options.
    </para>
   </step>
   <step>
    <para>
     Start the VM installation.
    </para>
   </step>
   <step>
    <para>
     For Windows 2003, at the very beginning of the installation there is an
     option to press <guimenu>F6</guimenu> for an OEM SCSI disk installation.
     At that time, press <guimenu>F6</guimenu>. The VirtIO disk driver from the
     <emphasis>vfd</emphasis> can then be selected and installed.
    </para>
   </step>
   <step>
    <para>
     For Windows 2008* and newer, on the <guimenu>Where do you want to install
     Windows</guimenu> screen, select <guimenu>Load driver</guimenu> and follow
     the prompts. This will allow the VirtIO disk driver to be installed for
     the boot disk.
    </para>
   </step>
   <step>
    <para>
     Continue the Windows installation.
    </para>
   </step>
   <step>
    <para>
     After the VM is completely installed, the remaining VirtIO drivers can be
     installed by copying the <command>VMDP-WIN-VERSION.exe</command> from the
     <emphasis>iso</emphasis> onto the VM's disk
     and performing a normal <command>VMDP-WIN-VERSION.exe</command>
     installation.
    </para>
   </step>
  </procedure>
 </sect2>

 <sect2 xml:id="sec-vmdp-driver-xen-instructions">
  <title>Additional Xen setup instructions</title>
  <para>
   Setup and the <option>/boot_vscsi</option> option: The Xen &vmdpa; SCSI driver
   is capable of controlling a physical SCSI disk such as
   <filename>/dev/sdb</filename>. To run the &vmdpa; SCSI driver on the boot disk,
   use setup <option>/boot_vscsi</option>. If the <option>/boot_vscsi</option>
   option is not used with setup, <command>pvctrlw.exe</command> can be used
   later to indicate that the &vmdpa; SCSI driver should control the boot disk.
   Before using the <option>/boot_vscsi</option> option or
   <command>pvctrlw.exe</command>, the VM's configuration file must already
   contain the necessary SCSI information for the boot disk: the disk line
   needs to reference the physical disk, for example
   <emphasis>disk=['phy:/dev/sdb,...']</emphasis> and there must be a
   <emphasis>vscsi= </emphasis>line that corresponds to the physical disk. SCSI
   devices and disks, other than the boot disk, that are to be controlled by
   the &vmdpa; SCSI driver are not placed in the <emphasis>disk=</emphasis> line
   but are only referenced in the <emphasis>vscsi=</emphasis> line.
  </para>
 </sect2>

 <sect2 xml:id="sec-vmdp-driver-uninstall">
  <title>Uninstalling the driver pack</title>
  <para>
   To uninstall the &productname;, execute the
   <command>uninstall.exe</command> from the <filename>\Program
   Files\vmdp</filename> folder. <command>Uninstall.exe</command> will
   uninstall the &productname; and remove the associated
   files for the hypervisor that the VM is currently running on. The
   <option>/virtio</option> and <option>/xen</option> parameters forces the
   uninstall of those drivers reqardless of the running hypervisor. When
   uninstalling, it is important to <emphasis>reboot</emphasis> the VM on the
   currently running hypervisor to all allow the uninstall to clean up
   additional files and registry entries on reboot.
  </para>
 </sect2>

 <sect2 xml:id="sec-vmdp-driver-upgrade">
  <title>Upgrading the driver pack</title>
  <para>
   <command>Setup.exe</command> can be used to update most existing
   installations. To update an existing installation do the following:
  </para>
  <procedure>
   <step>
    <para>
     Download the <command>VMDP-WIN-VERSION.exe</command> to your Windows VM.
    </para>
   </step>
   <step>
    <para>
     Run <command>VMDP-WIN-VERSION.exe</command> to extract the installation
     program and support files into a subfolder of the folder containing
     <command>VMDP-WIN-VERSION.exe</command>.
    </para>
   </step>
   <step>
    <para>
     Run <command>Setup.exe</command> from the root of the extracted subfolder
     and follow the on-screen instructions.
    </para>
   </step>
   <step>
    <para>
     Any <emphasis>Found New Hardware Wizard</emphasis> dialogs that pop up
     after the update can be ignored or canceled.
    </para>
   </step>
  </procedure>
  <para>
   With some older installations, setup cannot perform an update. In these
   cases, setup will inform you that the existing installation will need to be
   uninstalled first. Uninstall the existing installation. After being
   completely uninstalled, <filename>setup.exe</filename> can then be used to
   install the new files.
  </para>
 </sect2>

 <sect2 xml:id="sec-vmdp-driver-recover">
  <title>Recovering from a failure</title>
  <para>
   If a failure is caused by the driver pack, you can safely remove the driver
   pack and return to your previous system configuration.
  </para>
  <procedure>
   <step>
    <para>
     Shut down the virtual machine and reboot in safe mode.
    </para>
   </step>
   <step>
    <para>
     Uninstall the driver pack (see
     <xref linkend="sec-vmdp-driver-uninstall" xrefstyle="SectTitleOnPage"/>).
    </para>
   </step>
  </procedure>
 </sect2>

 <sect2 xml:id="sec-vmdp-driver-issue">
  <title>Known issues</title>
  <para>
   For information on known issues for this release, see the README file within
   the archive, or consult the &productname; guides.
  </para>
 </sect2>
</sect1>
